Guide to the Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Chapter Records, 1956-1984 AIS.1997.08
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Chapter Records
1956-1984
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania. Pittsburgh Chapter
AIS.1997.08
2.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Records of Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Chapter, includes Constitution, Minutes, Financial Reports, Presidential Files, Member Activities, Guides, Newsletters, and Scrapbooks, for the years 1956-1984.
History
The Pittsburgh Chapter of Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, founded by John and Eileen Shackelton, was established in the 1950s and incorporated in 1957. It is a non-profit organization founded "to promote opportunities for maximum independence of the physically handicapped in all aspects of daily living." The organization has been instrumental in assisting handicapped people with finding suitable housing, using public transportation, and making buildings and sidewalks accessible to those with physical challenges.
Scope and Content Notes
Records of Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Chapter, is organized into 6 series including Constitution, Minutes, Financial Reports, Presidential Files, Member Activities, Guides, and Newsletters, for the years 1956-1984. These series include bylaws, minutes, treasurer's reports, ledgers, correspondence, membership information, reports, newsletters, and scrapbooks
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Eileen Shackelton, April 2, 1997
Previous Citation
Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania, Pittsburgh Chapter Records, 1956-1984, AIS.1997.08, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Associations; People with disabilities -- Services for -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Open Doors for the Handicapped of Pennsylvania. Pittsburgh Chapter -- Archives; Shackelton, Eileen; Shackelton, John
- Constitution, 1957-1982; I.
  - Constitution/Bylaws, 1957-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charter (Correspondence), 1954-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - State Organization, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - State Chapter (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Butler Chapter (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1969-1984; II.
  - Executive Board, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General Meeting, September 1969 - May 1971; 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Financial Reports, 1972-1984; III.
  - Financial Secretary (Membership Slips), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Financial Secretary Records, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Financial Secretary, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1977-1978, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - Treasurer's Reports and Balance Sheets, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
  - Cash Journal, 1972-1978, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
  - Ledger, January 1977 - January 1978, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 20-21)
  - Balance Sheets and Cash Journal, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Profit and Loss Statement, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Sales Tax Reforms, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Presidential Files, 1977-1984; IV.
  - Eileen Shackelton, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Presidential Files, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - Correspondence - Eileen Shackelton, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Correspondence - General, 1981-1982, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letters, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - First Draft of Letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Member Activities, 1974-1984; V.
  - Activities Announcements (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Attendance Book, January 1978-September 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Membership Directories (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Membership Mailing, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Information to Members, 1980-1982, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Ramp the Curb Day", August 26, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Handicapped Sidewalk Ramps Maps (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Independent Living, 1978-1980, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 40-41)
  - Housing for the Handicapped - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Vocation Rehabilitation (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Transportation (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Requests for Information/Service, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Audited Financial Statements (Neighborhood Assistance Contract), June 30, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Accessibility Reports (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Proposals for Legislation (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Legislation Information (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Letters to Legislators (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hearing Reports/Senate Bills, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 52-54)
- Guides/Newsletters, 1956-1983; VI.
  - Guides to Pittsburgh for the Handicapped (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Catalogs for Handicapped Equipment (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Newsletters, March 1967-May 1983 (Box 2, Folder 57-61)
  - Pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Clippings File (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Programs to Christmas Parties (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Scrapbook, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Additions, 1982-1988; VII.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Additions series contains financial reports, presidential correspondence, chapter newsletters, and a corporate record book. The collection additions were made June, 2016.
  - Financial Statements (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - General, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mon-Yough Chapter, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Altoona Chapter, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Record Book, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)